after I got divorced I was trying to
figure out the best way that I could
help and I was kind of waning I didn't
have a religion at the time uh had been
Christian most of my life Mormon and I
ran across I I wanted to be a teacher I
wanted to do more than just chase down
memory leaks and tattle tell software
for IBM um I wanted to make more of my
life you could call it a midlife crisis
whatever you want to call it and at the
time um a kind teacher reached out to me
that I met over Twitter which is is a
whole you know personal professional
Learning Network conversation to have
about that there's been separate video
about why that's important and this
person suggested to me you know we we
started a dialogue and and um actually
met a lot of teachers through this
person and um at one point I I we were
talking about what is the best way to
help because I was like I wanted to be a
part of the solution instead of part of
the problem and that was when she said
very Point Blank she's like you know
what you don't have to become a teacher
you don't have to dedicate yourself to
switching out and and you know starting
a company or any of the things that I
ended up doing you need to help us
stabilize their home and I she didn't
say it like that but that's what it was
and that was when I set out on a quest
to find out what is the best way to
stabilize as many homes as I could and
one of the things that I found I I
started going to all kinds of different
churches I didn't care care about the
church um people would ask me what's
your religion and I'd say I don't know
what church do you go to I go whatever
one's doing the most good honestly I
didn't care and I went to the unitarians
that was one of my favorite and I you
know I went to the big mega churches
which were a lot of Flash and not a lot
of stuff going on um boy I have a story
about that about this this this campaign
they were doing to help people in Africa
when I started asking about the pictures
of the kids that they were doing they
told me that they actually weren't real
yeah that that was just to help I mean
that I I could do all day on that um but
the the main thing was there was a there
was a a charity uh downtown and uh it
was called the morille Christian Mission
and and I I I ran the 5K like five years
ago you know on Twitch actually live
streamed it but they have a program
called the bridges out of poverty and
that's the point of this video the
bridges out of poverty program is this
you know science-based approach to
helping people Bridge a gap from poverty
and to and it's also really good for
helping uh everyone understand the
different mental models that are out
there and when I talk about mental
models there's like you know there's
like there's like low income mind
mindset there's there's you know medium
and then there's high and they all have
it's just really good and then it then
it became but and I did I actually
volunteered uh and helped many families
they would dedicate a team to a specific
uh family to try to help them and even
so they still only had a 50% success
rate overcoming societal poverty and the
issues that are happening is a really
really big deal it's hard it's like a
war you know we talk about cyber
security warfare that's happening and
all this other things that's going on
but but but it is literally just as hard
as that to to overcome institutionalized
poverty particularly in late stage
capitalism so I'm just this video is
just to put this book out there if you
want to understand from a science
perspective what is going on with
poverty and maybe question some of your
base assumptions about it I I strongly
recommend it